<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Women, | Breaking into the New York tech scene isn’t as hard as it sounds]]></title>
  <link href="http://asialindsay.github.io/blog/categories/women/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://asialindsay.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-10T15:13:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://asialindsay.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Asia Lindsay]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking Into the New York Tech Scene Isn’t as Hard as It Sounds]]></title>
    <link href="http://asialindsay.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/my-first-post-on-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-10T14:52:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://asialindsay.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/my-first-post-on-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My journey into tech wasn’t clear cut. I started my career as a linguist for TED, and while I was there I started the TED Coding Club with one of the web developers, Alex Dean. I rallied the people on the ground and he Skyped in from South Dakota to help with the technical questions- it was awesome!</p>

<p>After that I realized there was something in coding and it was worth looking into. The problem was bootcamps are expensive and it’s a pretty huge decision to make, so I looked to the community to learn more.</p>

<p>I just started asking around- I found people on LinkedIn who had done the General Assembly intensive course and asked what they thought of it. I signed up for a tonne of newsletters and started going to events. At first it felt a little odd as I didn’t know much about coding, but I got to the stage where I was beginning to bump into people I knew at events- it’s a really warm community, especially for women.</p>

<p><b>Scholarships, scholarships, scholarships</b> - they are out there. There are definitely more for women but I’ve seen some for men too. Take full advantage of these. <a href="https://www.girldevelopit.com/">Girl Develop It</a> sends out weekly emails with coding opportunities and job offers and more often than not, a scholarship or discount chucked in for good measure. Through this I got a place to go to the <a href="https://www.womentechmakers.com">Google Women Techmakers Summit</a> and was offered a discount for <a href="http://lesbianswhotech.org">Lesbians Who Tech</a>. I also got won the women’s scholarship to learn Rails from the lovely people at <a href="www.onemonth.com">One Month</a>  - they give away 10 scholarships per month.</p>

<p>My mentor, Rebecca Garcia, has also been an invaluable resource- she’s helped me navigate the waters of applying to multiple bootcamps and invites me along to events with her.</p>

<p>Lastly, short courses, meetups and hackathons- more and more are cropping up every day. <a href="https://www.womenwhocode.com">Women Who Code</a>, <a href="www.ladieswhocode.com">Ladies Who Code</a> and <a href="www.hackerhours.org">Hacker Hours</a> are all excellent resources. Volunteering is great practise because it reinforces your own coding knowledge. My mentor also turned me onto <a href="http://www.coderdojonyc.org">CoderDojo NYC</a>, a group she runs that teaches kids from 7 to 17 about web, game and app development.</p>

<p>There’s a lot out there- you just have to start looking. Check out <a href="http://www.geekgirlweb.com/resources">this post</a> for more resources. You can also see this post on <a href="https://medium.com/@asialindsay/breaking-into-the-new-york-tech-scene-isn-t-as-hard-as-it-sounds-23cb5a118fc6">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
